Hudson Diggs Bailey

 $my \ full \ name \ {\rm at \ gmail}$ Chicago, IL | 610 755 5471

EDUCATION

University of Chicago || Chicago, IL

M.A. | Social Sciences | Aug 2017

Oberlin College || Oberlin, OH

B.A. || Neuroscience || May 2015

SUMMARY

Inter-disciplinary background in Cultural Anthropology & Neuroscience with diverse interests in healthcare, technology, theory & policy || Independently-driven collaborator working across fields || Practical, highly resourceful & big picture-oriented researcher with an anthropologist's eye for details ||

SKILLS & TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

- Research & Analysis: research design, secondary research, semi-structured interviews, transcription & interview coding, informed consent, IRB applications, quantitative data analysis, interaction effects || SPSS, Excel, ELAN, Python
- Communication: concise writing, proof-reading, interdisciplinary communication, team projects, scientific presentation || Docs, Word, Slides, PowerPoint, Markdown
- Coordination: Scheduling, note & reference organization, automation tools, spreadsheet programming, respositories & version control || Google Apps, Calendar, Zotero, ReadCube, Git, Excel, Atom
- Production: layout editing, photo editing, static websites, figure making & data visualization, modeling, rigging, rendering, interactive games || Illustrator, Photoshop, GIMP, 3DS Max, Maya, Vizard, Oculus Rift, Jekyll, LATEX
- Languages: English (native), Spanish (intermediate)

RESEARCH PRESENTATIONS

- 2017 University of Chicago: Master's Thesis Research Seminar
 - Interfaced Affects: Computing, Mediation & Care in Neuropsychiatric Monitoring
- 2015 Annual Society for Neuroscience Conference: Poster Presentation
 - Toward a Naturalistic Model of Multisensory Integration 2015 Synesthesia Symposium: Talk & panel discussion
- on Perspectives on Synaesthesia from Neuroscience

 Multisensory Integration in Immersive Virtual Environments
- 2014 Annual Biomedical Research Conference for Minority Students: Poster Presentation Audio-Visual Integration Varies with Stimulus & Background Complexity in a Virtual Environment

AWARDS & SCHOLARSHIPS

- 2016 University of Chicago Social Sciences Division || Merit-Based Full Tuition Scholarship
- 2015 Oberlin College Neuroscience Dept. || Department Student Travel Award
- 2014 Annual Biomedical Research Conference for Minority Students || ABRCMS Full Travel Award
- 2013-2015 Oberlin College || Class of 1928 Scholarship
- 2013 Oberlin College || Class of 1961 Endowed Scholarship Fund

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

University of Chicago, Anthropology Dept. || Chicago, IL

Graduate Student Researcher || Sept 2016- Aug 2017

- Conducted independent qualitative research on technology development in the emerging field of "digital psychiatry"
- Used a variety of qualitative research methods, particularly participant observation & semi-structured interviews, in addition to secondary research across a range of social science & medical disciplines
- Worked across multiple disciplines (e.g., neuro-psychiatry, machine learning, anthropology) to tell a complex narrative of how physicians understand digital technology, capital investment & surveillance in relation to their own patients

Oberlin College, Neuroscience Dept. || Oberlin, OH

Research Assistant || Sept 2013 - July 2015

- Designed & independently coded virtual reality Oculus Rift application for Oberlin College's Multisensory Neuroscience Lab; forthcoming publication
- Standardized & updated lab data management practices by building streamlined analysis programs to integrate data across multiple behavioral & neurophysiological studies
- Acting lab manager for scheduling & correspondence with study participants

Oberlin College, Anthropology Dept. || Oberlin, OH

Research Assistant || Feb 2015 - June 2015

- Conducted background & supplementary research for professor's book-length ethnography on environmentalism in war
- Produced literature reviews on environmental economics, systems ecology & journalism involving NGO & military activity

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

Varsity Tutors || Chicago, IL

GRE Tutor || Oct 2017- present

 One-on-one tutoring for Graduate Records Examination (GRE) quantitative & verbal sections

Conifer Research || Chicago, IL

Logger | Aug - Sept 2017

• Temp position transcribing & coding interviews

CoNECt, University of Illinois at Chicago || Chicago, IL

Volunteer Research Assistant & Technologist | July - Oct 2016

 Facilitated early-stage virtual reality (VR) project design for collaborative project between psychiatry department and engineering school for an experimental Body Dysmorphia exposure therapy

Oberlin College, Philosophy Dept. || Oberlin, OH

 $Grading\ Assistant\ \ \mathcal{C}\ Peer\ Tutor\ ||\ Sept\ 2013\ -\ Dec\ 2014$

 Graded assignments & tutored students in undergraduate philosophy course on symbolic logic